

KENNETH MAPLES

Desktop Support Technician

OVERVIEW

Over 17 years' experience in systems configuration, deployment, administration and support in Windows XP,7, 8.1, NT, 2000, 2003, 2008, 2012R2 Server and PC environments. This includes configuration, and deployment of client/server LAN's, wireless networking, software and operating system migrations, and server/network administration.

WORK EXPERIENCE

NASA/A.I. Solutions, Cape Canaveral, FL Senior System Administrator March 2011 to Current

- Administration of NASA servers for the Launch Services Program, including 2008 & 2012 web servers, Microsoft SQL 2008, & 2012 servers, and file servers.
- Analyzing system logs, and performing backups with EMC Networker.
- Building Windows Server 2008, & 2012R2 systems, including VMWARE vShere5 virtual systems, applying monthly patches, ensuring FDCC security and compliance.
- Adding, removing, or updating user account information, resetting passwords, in Active Directory.
- Administration of EMC VNX 5400 SAN

NASA/A.I. Solutions, Cape Canaveral, FL Desktop Specialist June 2008 to March 2011

- NASA Kennedy Space Center Florida, performed desktop support functions, managed tickets in the BMC TrackIT system.
- Configuration and deployment of NASA engineering workstations, and laptops...
- Worked with security to ensure all systems are FDCC Compliant.
- Lead in planning and deployment of McAfee Endpoint Encryption.
- Implemented Ghost 11.5 and sysprep in the creation of standardized Windows XP and 7 system images



Harris Corporation, Melbourne, FL Help Desk Analyst October 2007 to May 2008

- First level call center support for Harris employees.
- Supported Microsoft Office 2003 & 2007 Outlook and Exchange.
- Supported multiple corporate divisions.

CompuCom, Blue Ash, OH Remote Desktop Technician January 2007 to September 2007

- Provided level II desktop support for GE employees at remote locations using remote desktop tools.
- Troubleshoot problems, and configured Dell workstations, Dell notebooks, and Lenovo Laptops

Valcom, Itasca, IL Server Monitoring Specialist March 2005 to December 2006

- Contractor for Duke Energy in Cincinnati, OH, worked as SOC personnel supporting server and network monitoring.
- Monitored systems such as Openview, used monitoring applications (Aprisma Spectrum) and Nagios, environmental monitoring packages (HP Site Scan), HP Insight Manager.
- Troubleshoot and assisted in resolving Exchange email issues, determined and corrected SQL and Oracle database related issues.
- Corrected server issues, performed application installations, server security scans, security patching, and rebooted servers.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Indiana Vocational Technical College - 1985

Associates Degree Architectural Drafting

New Horizons Orlando Course, 2013 VMware® vSphere Install, Configure, Manage v5.1

Global Knowledge Course, 2014

Microsoft Official Course M6419 Configuring, Managing, and Maintaining Server 2008 R2

EMC VNX Unified Storage Management - Online ILT, 2015